♪ Here we are going far ♪
♪ to save all that we love ♪
♪ If we give all we’ve got ♪
♪ we will make it through ♪
♪ Here we are like a star ♪
♪ shining bright
on your world today ♪
♪ Make evil go away ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we’ll
withstand it all ♪
♪ Code Lyoko be there
when you call ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we
will stand real tall ♪
♪ Code Lyoko
stronger after all ♪
(PULSING)
(SINISTER MUSIC)
Here we have the nanosphere
that he nanotech services company
was kind enough to lend us.
Who can tell us
what nanotechnology is?
Jeremie, go on.
It’s microscopic-sized technology.
There are nano motors,
nano circuit boards, and nano gears.
Exactly.
In the medical field, for example,
scientists are developing nano doctors,
tiny machines which will be able
to travel through our bodies to combat disease.
Scientific research, however,
still has a long way to go.
Are these robots capable of fighting
pimples, cellulite, and things like that?
Yes, they can, but the priority
is for more serious illnesses.
(LAUGHTER)
And nanotechnology
can’t do a thing about stupidity!
Poor Sissi! What a shame!
All right, now. Quiet down.
So, this nanosphere is used
to make microscopic devices.
Strange…
it hasn’t been cleaned properly.
There’s gelatin inside.
Looks like the greasy stuff
Odd puts on his hair every day.
Well, since you think
you’re so clever, Ulrich,
why don’t you take a sample
for us to examine?
The gelatin is used as a culture
where nanodevices can develop.
It looks an awful lot like jam.
Sorry, but I just couldn’t resist!
I’ll get you for that, Odd!
This is a science class,
children, not a comedy club!
Wow, this nanotechnology is incredible.
Now there’s a field
I’d like to work on in the future.
I have enough trouble
with normal-sized technology,
much less microscopic.
Hey, that looks good!
Can I have some?
Here.
I warned you!
Yeah…
but taking advantage
of my sweet tooth wasn’t fair!
I said I’d--
Ulrich! What is it?
It’s my head, I--
What’s going on around here?
Ulrich passed out.
I’ll take him to the infirmary.
He was just fine this morning.
I know, it’s really weird.
Hmm…
All right.
Get some rest now, Ulrich.
What are you doing here?
I wanted to find out how Ulrich was.
Much better. He’s asleep.
Just a second, can I see him?
I don’t know, I, uh…
You see, I’m his best friend!
Oh, all right, but not for too long.
You’re so handsome when you sleep.
Where am I, anyway?
In the infirmary. You passed out.
The infirmary?
What infirmary?
Who am I! What’s my name?
Uh, Ulrich!
Ulrich?
You must’ve hit your head
when you fell down.
And who are you?
Me? I’m Sissi.
Sissi!
Your sweetheart!
Watch it!
Well, Ulrich,
when are you gonna admit
you’re mad about me, huh?
You’re kidding…
I’m allergic to anyone who’s conceited!
You’re your own favorite fan club!
(LAUGHTER)
My sweetheart?
Well, our patient is awake, I see.
Ulrich, how are you?
Uh…
Oh, much, much better!
I’ll take him to his room!
Are you sure you’re all right?
What is this, an epidemic?
Come on, hurry!
Well, what do you know?
See those three kids over there?
They’re your worst enemies!
But why?
Hey, it’s Ulrich!
What’s going on?
Why is he with Sissi?
You feeling better, good buddy?
Who are you, huh?
Leave me alone, creep!
Come one, Ulrich, it’s me! Odd!
That’s enough. Can’t you see?
He doesn’t want to know you,
so stay away from us, understand?
What’s the matter with him?
Ulrich, these are your good friends,
Nicholas and Herb.
Huh?
He forgets things!
You’d better remind him!
I’m, um, very thirsty.
You know what
would be good for you?
A walk in the park!
Here, thanks!
He didn’t recognize us, it’s crazy!
Could be amnesia…
Let’s go see what the nurse says.
Good idea.
I’ve gotta bring him back to his senses.
Sissi and Ulrich?
Can you believe that?
Here, you need the energy.
Ulrich, what do you feel knowing
you’re with the prettiest girl in school?
Well, to be honest, uh, nothing.
What did you say?
What I mean is…
you’re really not my type.
Hmph.
Well, at least he’s not
completely out of his head yet.
Hm?
Hey, what are you doing? Spying on me!
Uh, no! I-I was just--
You’re a liar!
Ulrich, cut that out!
We’re buddies, remember?
That’s not what she says,
so get out of here, and make it fast!
Okay, okay, don’t get all worked up!
Ulrich? Are you alright? Come on!
Ulrich and Sissi. Just the two of you!
This could be
the beginning of a big romance!
Ah, forget it!
She’s gonna be a
pain in the neck the whole time!
Come sit down, you need to rest.
I’m sorry, but…
What I need is to be alone.
The answer is no!
Can’t you see I have no time!
I don’t know what’s happening,
but it’s an epidemic!
We can stay and help you if you want.
The best way to help
is to stay out of my way!
Maybe Odd had more luck.
No doubt about it,
Ulrich’s got amnesia.
I thought he was
gonna slug me just now!
It’s a real epidemic
according to the nurse.
But you don’t just catch amnesia.
It’s not contagious.
Something’s really weird.
We’d better ask a doctor about it.
Too bad that nano doctors don’t exist yet.
Nano doctor…
now I understand!
Huh?
Misses Hertz?
Oh, where am I?
You’ll be alright.
Look at this.
It’s the gelatin from this morning!
What are those ugly creatures?
What I was afraid of.
They’re nano viruses.
And XANA must have created them
to attack memory cells.
That means that it is contagious.
Like all viruses, you can catch it
from food, contact, sneezing…
Soon, the whole school
will be infected, including us.
A world without memory…
Under XANA’s control.
Let’s go to the factory fast.
Aelita must be in danger on Lyoko.
And Ulrich! We’re gonna need him!
No, Odd, it’s Ulrich who needs our help.
He’ll only get well if we
can deactivate the tower.
Yumi’s right.
Besides, if he can’t remember anything,
he won’t be much good to us.
E-Excuse me,
i-is my room around here?
Has everyone gone crazy around here?
Third door on the right.
Uh…
I don’t know who you are,
but it seems we’re friends.
Hm…
(LAUGHING)
Not a minute to lose!
Huh? What’s going on around here?
(GROANING)
Aah!
Ulrich, I’m so glad you came.
You really know how to
cheer someone up.
Yeah!
Aelita!
I haven’t seen anything to worry about
either in the forest or in the desert area.
Okay, beam yourself
over to the mountains.
I’ll send Yumi and Odd to the glacier.
The activated tower’s gotta be somewhere.
Okay, ready for the north pole?
We’re on our way, Aelita.
Okay.
We’re in the tunnel in the park.
10 seconds to transfer time.
Transfer Odd.
Transfer Yumi.
Scanner Odd.
Scanner Yumi.
Virtualization.
Okay, take the access on your right!
Right, boss!
Aelita, anything new?
No.
I haven’t been all over yet,
but still no vibrations.
Be careful.
Yumi and Odd are pretty far away.
Ah…aaah!
Watch out!
Yumi, you just lost 20 life points!
Jeremie, we’ve got a welcoming committee.
Don’t panic, there’s just one Krab.
But it means the
activated tower can’t be far.
I’ll warn Aelita.
He’s coming towards you, Yumi!
Don’t worry, he just wants to
play hide-and-seek.
Playful little beast.
Wow!
Ulrich!
What am I doing here?
What kind of place is this?
I can’t tell you now,
we’ve got an emergency.
Look, I can’t remember anything,
but I know I have
something important to do here.
Tell me what it is.
Well, uh…sure, why not?
Once you’re on Lyoko, you’ll have to
do something, amnesia or not.
What’s Lyoko?
It’s, uh…
Look…see that pillar behind you?
You’ve gotta slide up one level.
You’ll see a few scanners.
Get into one of them and just wait.
You’ll get all the answers you want.
Yoo-hoo!
Over here!
Hey, crabby!
Hiyah!
Target hit!
Nice going, Yumi!
Two things, guys.
One, Aelita’s waiting
on the other side of the glacier.
And two?
Two, Ulrich’s on the way.
Ulrich?
I’ll wait for him here.
Better hurry!
Transfer Ulrich.
Scanner Ulrich.
Virtualization!
Ouch!
Welcome to the virtual world, Ulrich!
What is this place?
What are we here for?
To fight, of course.
To fight?
I don’t know how to fight!
But of course you do!
You just forgot, but I will refresh your memory.
Okay, come on!
Hello, Aelita!
I found the activated tower.
We’re almost there!
Lead the way!
You’re just dodging my blows!
Don’t you have a weapon?
I have a few arrows,
but I’d rather save them for now.
And I don’t want to
hurt you with them, either.
Oh, yeah? No kidding.
We’re almost there.
Yeah, it seems almost too easy.
I have a funny feeling about this.
I’m sick of always being right.
That way!
Four against one.
Well, it’s better than five or six.
Hang in there, girls,
I’ll try to send you reinforcements.
First, let’s get rid of two of them.
(CELESTIAL HUMMING)
Hurry! It’s not gonna hold for long!
Hey, you ought to save your strength.
You’re gonna need it.
Why, are there other levels?
I like it here! It’s a video game, but for real!
Yeah, but now it’s time to stop.
Aelita and Yumi need you.
Huh? Who said that?
Jeremie. Come on!
Hey, wait! We haven’t finished the game!
Again?
Yumi, be careful.
You’ve only got a few life points left.
Nice going, Yumi.
One to go!
Hurry, Yumi! The wall’s not gonna last!
There! I win the game!
Yeah, but you beat an ally!
What?
Now that you know who your friends are,
it’s time to meet your enemies.
Huh? Enemies? What enemies?
They’re Krabs. Monsters created by XANA.
Listen, I can’t explain now.
Yumi and Aelita need our help.
And right now.
To get rid of them,
you have to hit the thing
on their shell that looks like an eye!
Sounds easy enough!
Laser arrow!
Ulrich! Aah!
What happened to her?
Nothing serious.
We’ve gotta protect Aelita!
I’ll take care of it.
It’s good to see Ulrich
with his memory back again.
You’re wrong, he’s still got amnesia!
Hm?
Yaaah!
Thanks for clearing the passage!
Huh? She’s leaving?
Uh, not exactly total recall.
Jeremie, I’m coming!
No, I’m Odd!
Here we go!
-Laser arrow!
-Impact!
Great, guys! You’re one heck of a team!
Is that it? No other players?
No, we can go home. The game’s over.
Huh? But how?
Magic. Watch.
Return to the past now.
Exactly.
In the medical field, for example,
scientists are developing nano doctors,
tiny machines which will be able
to travel through our bodies
to combat disease.
Scientific research, however,
still has a long way to go.
Are these robots capable of fighting
pimples, cellulite, and things like that?
Yes, they can, but the priority
is for more serious illnesses.
And nanotechnology
can’t do a thing about stupidity!
Poor Sissi. What a shame!
All right, now. Quiet down.
This nanosphere is used
to make microscopic devices.
Strange…it hasn’t been cleaned properly.
There’s gelatin inside.
Looks like the greasy stuff
Odd puts on his hair every day.
Since you think you’re clever, Ulrich,
why don’t you take a sample
for us to examine?
It’s used as a culture
where nanodevices can develop.
Anyway, it looks an awful lot like jam.
Let’s try to cook it! You never can tell!
Ulrich! What are you doing?
How dare you destroy school equipment!
I’ll have to punish you severely for that,
and it’s going to be
a punishment you won’t forget!
I hope not, Misses Hertz!
I sure hope not!
(LAUGHTER)
CLOSED CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY
REDDIT.COM/R/CODELYOKO